Guide to the Academic Council records, 1954-2000 UA.28.03.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Academic Council records
1954-2000
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Academic Council
UA.28.03.0001
30 Linear Feet
This collection contains materials of the Academic Council, established at Duke University in 1962. The Academic Council is a group of faculty members who provide representation of the body of Duke University faculty to the Administration, Board of Trustees, and other decision-making groups. Types of materials include minutes and associated materials, memoranda and correspondence, council and committee membership lists, new committee charges, reports, bylaws, policy documents and related proposals, financial records, and other records of the Academic Council and its committees. Major subjects include Duke University faculty, Duke University Administration, and Duke University Board of Trustees. Materials range in date from 1954-2000. English.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
Provenance
Transfer; 1967-2001; 67-63, 68-328, 69-45, 71-384, 73-69, 73-92, 73-115, 74-99, 74-109, 76-104, 77-12, 78-6, 79-78, 1981-119, 82-66, 82-103, 82-120, 85-57, 87-30, 90-9, 90-45, 91-94, 93-38, A94-131, 96-103, 96-129, A97-89, A98-82, A99-66, A2000-6, A2001-15, A2001-50.
Transfer UA2018.0044.
Historical Note
The Academic Council and the Executive Committee which it elects are the chief instruments of faculty governance at Duke University. The formation of an Academic Council was recommended in a March, 1962 report of the University Faculty's Committee on Faculty Organization, and authorized in a 1962 revision of the University Bylaws. The first meeting was held on October 18, 1962. The officers of the Academic Council, all elected from the faculty, are the Chairman, Vice Chairman, and Secretary. The Academic Council, the Executive Committee that it elects, and the University Policy and Planning Advisory Committee replaced the University Council as the primary vehicles for faculty representation and participation in the governance of the University. In 1972, the faculty granted to the Academic Council full power to act on their behalf. The Academic Council has become the principal open forum for discussion of all matters of interest to the University community. The minutes of the Council constitute an open record of discussion and opinion on all matters that the faculty deems important for University consideration.
Collection Overview
This collection contains materials of the Academic Council, established at Duke University in 1962. The Academic Council is a group of faculty members who provide representation of the body of Duke University faculty to the Administration, Board of Trustees, and other decision-making groups. The collection includes minutes and associated materials, memoranda and correspondence, council and committee membership lists, new committee charges, reports, bylaws, policy documents and related proposals, financial records, and other records of the Academic Council and its committees. Materials range in date from 1954-2000. Materials are continuously added to this collection.
Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University. Board of Trustees; Duke University. Academic Council
- Academic Council Minutes, 1962-2000.
  Scope and Contents note
  The Minutes series is maintained in chronological order and includes agendas, minutes and associated materials (such as committee reports and other attachments) for meetings of the Academic Council. Duplicates have been removed. There are no restrictions on access to this material. Minutes from recent meetings are maintained in the University Archives subject file.
  - 1962-1968 (Box 1)
  - 1968-1974 (Box 2)
  - 1974-1982 (Box 3)
  - 1982-1987 (Box 4)
  - 1987-1989 (Box 5)
  - 1989-1992 (Box 6)
  - 1992-1996 (Box 7)
  - 1996-1999 (Box 8)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 9)
- Records of the Academic Council Chair, 1961-1999.
  The Chair series is maintained in chronological order by administration, and consists of materials that University Archives has received from individuals who have chaired the Academic Council. Material may be added to this series as it is received. The original order of materials within each administration has been maintained.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Most of these records, including the minutes of the Executive Committee and the confidential files of the Chairman, are restricted for 10 years from date of origin. Among the confidential files of the Chair, however, are a few references to tenure consideration and appeals, generally marked "confidential." These materials would be governed by the restrictions for personnel information.
  - Academic Council, Formation of, 1961-1962, chair (Box 1)
  - Chair of Academic Council, personal files, 1962-1965 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, Personal Files 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, chair, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, Personal Files, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, chair, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, chair, 1967 Jan.-1967 June (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, chair, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1968 Sept.-1969 Feb. (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1969 Mar.-July (Box 1)
  - UPPAC, 1969 Feb. 12 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1968-1969, [3 folders] (Box 1)
  - Report on the Special Committee on Functions and Organizations of the Board of Trustees, Dec. 1969 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, chair. 1969 Feb.-1970 May (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, R.L. Watson, chair, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Academic Record, Transcripts, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Faculty and Staff Housing Committee, 1969 (Box 1)
  - University Judicial procedure, 1969 (Box 1)
  - University Judicial system, 1969 Nov. 10 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees, faculty representation, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Juris Doctor degree, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, 1969 May-1970 May (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees, Committee on University Governance, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Campus Unrest, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Duke University as Landlord Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Duke University Athletic Association, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Revised report on DUAA and Athletics, Master Copy and related Academic Council minutes, 1969 Nov. 20 (Box 2)
  - Report of Academic Council Committee on the Duke Athletic Program, 1969 Nov. 20 (Box 2)
  - ROTC, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Bachelor of Health Science degree, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Woodhall-Dobbs dinner, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Student Publications, Ad-Hoc Committee on, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee, confidential file, chairman's papers 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Trustee-Faculty Liaison Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Chairman, correspondence with Board of Trustees, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Chancellor, correspondence with, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - President, correspondence with, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Provost, correspondence with, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Communications from Faculty, 1964 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Dean of Faculty, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Chancellor Search Committee (and Antecedents), 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Highway 751, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - UFV-AC Committee on Faculty Referendum, Strandberg Proposal, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Duke Golf Course Policy Committee, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Security against Disruption, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, chair 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Executive Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee meetings, 1970 March, 1970 Sept.-May 1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Concerns of the Library Staff, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Ad Hoc Committee on Faculty representation, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Executive Committee, meeting minutes, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
  - Retroactive M. Divinity Degree, 1967, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Educational Facilities Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, TIAA-CREF, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - University Faculty, 1971 June (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, University Calendar and Schedule Business, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
  - Nepotism Policy, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, ROTC, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Self-Study Committee, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Benefits, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Report of the Subcommittee on the University Union of the Education Facilities Committee, 1971 Sept. 26 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, correspondence, 1971 May -1972 April (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, correspondence, 1972 April -December (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Executive Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Traffic Commission, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, chair, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, meeting notes, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Highway 751, Faculty Homesites Area, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Athletics, Pye report, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, Ad-Hoc Committee on Nature and Role of Academic Council, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, University Planning Committee, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Academic Council, meeting notes, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Duke University Environmental Concerns Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, membership and Regulations, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, chair 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Physical Education Department materials, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, Nominations to Committees, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, meeting notes, 1973 January- May (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, correspondence, 1973 January- May (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, Executive Committee meetings, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, Trustee Liaison Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Faculty, Demonstration School for Faculty Children and Others, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Schedule Committee, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council Secretary, Documents, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - Executive Committee agenda and minutes, Fall, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Executive Committee agenda and minutes, Spring, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, Executive Committee, 1973-1974, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Durham Schools Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, Budget, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, chairman's correspondence, Fall, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, chairman's correspondence, Spring, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, Roll, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - University, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - University, Epoch Campaign, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - University Planning Commission, minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Traffic Commission, 1973-1974 (Box 3)
  - Educational Facilities Committee, agenda and minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Duke University Environmental Concerns Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
  - Environmental Management, M.S. Degree, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Administrative and maintenance Costs, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Affirmative Action Grievance Procedure, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Fiftieth Anniversary, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Judicial Review, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Academic Council, April 1974 (Box 4)
  - Main Quadrangle, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Educational Facilities Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Academic Council, 1974-1975, [2 folders] (Box 4)
  - Executive Committee agenda and minutes, Fall, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Executive Committee agenda and minutes, Spring, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, Interim Policy, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Financial and Legal Risk Connected with Hospital Expansion, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - University Planning Commission minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Librarian Search Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Chairman's correspondence, Fall, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Chairman's correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Academic Council Roll, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Research Council, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Environmental Concerns Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Named Professorships, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Duke University Planning Commission, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Executive Committee, agenda and minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Educational Facilities Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Chairman's notes, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Chairman's notes 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Chairman's correspondence 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Barchas Collection, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Search Committee for Director of Barchas Collection, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - Academic Council, Hospital, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Academic Council, Hospital Expansion, 1973-1975 (Box 4)
  - National Center for Humanities, Advisory Center for, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - Medical Services, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Performing Arts Study, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Academic Council, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Traffic Commission, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
  - Committee to Study Science Libraries, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Bicycle Alternatives, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Graduate Program, Committee report, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Chairman's correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Budget, 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Educational Facilities Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 5)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity, 1973-1976 (Box 5)
  - Environmental Concerns Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Environmental Impact report, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Chairman's correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - President's Committee on Hunger, 1976 (Box 5)
  - University Planning Commission, 1973-1976 (Box 5)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Committee, minutes, 1973-1977 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee, agenda and minutes, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Benefits Committee, 1973-1976 (Box 5)
  - Faculty benefits (Box 5)
  - X-rated films, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Financial statements, 1971-1978 (Box 5)
  - Degrees, Honorary Degrees, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Marine Lab, Appendices, 1976 (Box 5)
  - University Maintenance, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee, agenda and minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  - Academic Council, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Traffic Commission, 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - University Center, 1973-1976 (Box 5)
  - Neurosciences, Ad-Hoc Committee on, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Student Health, Chancellor's Task Force on, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee, 1978-1979, [2 folders] (Box 5)
  - Academic Council, 1978-1979 (Box 5)
  - Academic Council, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Marine Lab, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Committee on Foreign Grants, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Committee to Consider Future Use of President's House, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Radioactive Waste Disposal, 1979 (Box 5)
  - Duke Press Ad-Hoc Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 5)
  - Circular A-21, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - Executive Council, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Performing Arts Council, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Education Appendices, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Department of Education, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Duke Translation Service, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Executive Committee. agenda and notes, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Retrenchment: Planning for the Eighties, 1978-1980 (Box 6)
  - Traffic appeals, 1973-1980 (Box 6)
  - Department of Sociology, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Sociology Appendices, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Dean's Council, minutes, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Duke-UNC Joint Press Committee, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Retrenchment documents, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Ad-Hoc Committee on Forestry School, 1964; 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Faculty Scholarship Fund, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Planning Committee, minutes, 1979-1980 (Box 6)
  - Academic Council, 1980 (Box 6)
  - School of Forestry (Box 6)
  - Forestry Appendices, 1980 (Box 6)
  - General Appendices, Retrenchment, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Department of Health, Physical Education and Recreation, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, Duke Preschool, 1980 (Box 6)
  - School of Nursing, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Nursing Appendices, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Publications Board, 1973-1980 (Box 6)
  - Planning Committee, General Documents, 1979-1981 (Box 6)
  - Weisfeld Case, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Energy Management Council, 1988-1981 (Box 6)
  - Faculty Handbooks Revisions, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Faculty Hearing Committee, J. Connolly and J. Dearlove, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - Computer Science Enterprise Company, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
  - Academic Council, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Draft of University Agreement with Nixon, 1981 (Box 6)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, Duke Phytotron, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Long Range Planning Committee, Ad-Hoc Panel on Duke Primate Center, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - Chairman, Academic Council, Nixon Library, 1981-1982 (Box 6)
  - East Campus, Committee on Future of, 1978-1982 (Box 6)
  - Academic Council, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Academic Council meetings
    - 1982 Sept. 16 (Box 7)
    - 1982 Oct. 21 (Box 7)
    - 1982 Nov. 18 (Box 7)
    - 1982 Dec. 16 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Jan. 20 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Feb. 17 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Mar. 17 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Apr. 21 (Box 7)
    - 1983 May 5 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Sept. 15 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Oct. 20 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Nov. 17 (Box 7)
    - 1983 Dec. 15 (Box 7)
    - 1984 Jan. 19 (Box 7)
    - 1984 Feb. 16 (Box 7)
    - 1984 Mar. 15 (Box 7)
    - 1984 Apr. 19 (Box 7)
    - 1984 May 3 (Box 7)
  - Academic Council, chair. Records of meetings of the Board of Trustees and the Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees.
    - Board of Trustees 1982 Sept. 24-25 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1982 Nov. 2 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees 1982 Dec. 10-11 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1983 Jan. 14 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees 1983 Feb. 25-26 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1983 Apr. 8 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees, 1983 May 6-7 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1983 June 10 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees, 1983 Sept. 23-24 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees, 1983 Dec. 9-10 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1983 Nov. 4 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1984 Jan. 20 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1984 Apr. 6 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees, 1984 March 2-3 (Box 8)
    - Board of Trustees, 1984 May 4-5 (Box 8)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 15 June 1984 (Box 9)
    - Board of Trustees, 28-29 Sept. 1984 (Box 9)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 2 Nov. 1984 (Box 9)
    - Board of Trustees 7-8 Dec. 1984 (Box 9)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 25 Jan. 1985 (Box 9)
    - Board of Trustees 1-2 March 1985 (Box 9)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees 5 April 1985 (Box 9)
    - Board of Trustees 3-4 May 1985 (Box 9)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 14 June 1985 (Box 9)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 23 August 1985 (Box 9)
    - Board of Trustees 27-28 Sept. 1985 (Box 9)
    - Executive Committee of the Board of Trustees, 1 Nov. 1985 (Box 9)
    - Board of Trustees 6-7 Dec. 1985 (Box 9)
- Records of the Academic Council Faculty Secretary, 1984-1987, 1990-1998.
  The Faculty Secretary series consists of materials that University Archives has received from individuals who have served as Faculty Secretary of the Academic Council. Material may be added to this series as it is received. The records dating from 1984-1987 are in folders organized by Academic Council meeting date and consist primarily of notes and documents pertaining to those meetings. The records from 1990-1998 are in volumes bound with metal fasteners. Organized, for the most part, by meeting dates for the Executive Committee of the Academic Council, these records consist primarily of agendas, minutes, notes and related documents pertaining to those Executive Committee meetings.
  These records, including the minutes of the Executive Committee, are restricted for 10 years from date of origin.
  - Academic Council, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Academic Council, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Council minutes and notes, 1985-1990
    - 1985 April 25 (Box 1)
    - 1985 May 2 (Box 1)
    - 1985 May 9 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Sept. (Box 1)
    - 1985 Oct. 17 (Box 1)
    - 1985 Nov. (Box 1)
    - 1986 Jan. (Box 1)
    - 1986 Feb. 20 (Box 1)
    - 1986 March (Box 1)
    - 1986 April 3 (Box 1)
    - 1986 April (Box 1)
    - 1986 May (Box 1)
    - 1986 September 1 (Box 1)
    - 1986 October (Box 1)
    - 1986 November (Box 1)
    - 1987 Jan. (Box 1)
    - 1987 Feb. (Box 1)
    - 1987 March (Box 1)
    - 1987 April (Box 1)
    - 1987 May (Box 1)
    - 1987 Sept. (Box 1)
    - 1990 February 01 - 1990 June 27 (Box 1)
    - 1990 August 15 - 1990 December 05 (Box 1)
    - 1990 December 12 - 1991 April 03 (Box 1)
    - 1991 April 10 - 1991 June 14 (Box 2)
    - 1991 August 20 - 1991 December 03 (Box 2)
    - 1991 December 10 - 1992 May 05 (Box 2)
    - 1990 May 19 - 1992 August 18 (Box 2)
    - 1992 August 26 - 1992 December 01 (Box 2)
    - 1992 December 08 - 1993 April 28 (Box 2)
    - 1993 May 05 - 1993 September 14 (Box 3)
    - 1993 September 21 - 1994 January 17 (Box 3)
    - 1994 Jan 24-May 9 (Box 3)
    - 1994 May 23-Nov. 14 (Box 3)
    - 1994 Nov. 21-1995 Mar. 27 (Box 3)
    - 1995 Apr. 3-Sept. 25 (Box 3)
    - 1995 Oct. 2-1996 Apr. 8 (Box 4)
    - 1996 Apr. 15-Oct. 7. (Box 4)
    - 1996 Oct. 14-1997 Mar. 31 (Box 4)
    - 1997 Apr. 7-Oct. 14 (Box 4)
    - 1997 Oct. 21-1998 Mar. 4 (Box 4)
    - 1998 Mar. 11-May 13 (Box 4)
- Records of Academic Council Committees.
  This series includes material that University Archives has received from representatives of various standing and ad hoc committees of the Academic Council. Contains restricted materials.
  - Administrative Oversight Committee (Box 1)
    - History, 1982
      - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
      - 1983, [2 folders] (Box 1)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 1)
    - Undergraduate Financial Aid Budget Review, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Budget Review, Marine Lab, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Development Budget Review
      - 1984 (Box 1)
      - 1985 (Box 1)
      - 1986 (Box 1)
  - Ad-Hoc Committee on Duke Athletics (Box 2)
    - Report, 1969 (Box 2)
    - The 'Good' of College Football, Packaged Facts (Box 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Questionnaires for students, faculty, and alumni, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Department of Health and Physical Education
      - Summarized curricula outlines, men's, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Department of Health and Physical Education, Department of Health and Physical Education, staff manual, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1968 (Box 2)
    - Statistics and budget 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Committee reports 1968-1969 (Box 2)
      Committee reports are RESTRICTED.
    - Academic Council minutes, annotated, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
      Includes Appointment of Athletic Review Committee
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Unlabeled, [3 folders] (Box 2)
    - Duplicates (Box 2)
  - East Campus Committee, Records, 1979-1982, [2 folders] (Box 3)
  - Faculty and Staff Housing, Committee on, Records, 1967-1970, 1979
    - Sidewalks, Bicyclewalk, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1968-1971 (Box 3)
    - Reports, 1964-1972 (Box 3)
    - Open Housing (Box 3)
    - Highway 751, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
    - Information on Faculty Policies at Other Universities (Box 3)